Finding Aid for School of Art and Design (University of Michigan) publications, 1947-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
School of Art and Design (University of Michigan) publications 1947-2010, 1985-2007
University of Michigan. School of Art and Design.
2 linear feet
0513 Bimu C676 2
Publications produced by the School of Art and its subunits, including brochures, bulletins, calendars, college catalogs, exhibition catalogs, newsletters, and student publications.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received from the School of Art and Design (Donor # 7510 ) periodically.
The collection is open to research.
See finding aid for the School of Art and Design record group.
The Publications series (1.0 linear foot) consists of two subseries: Unit Publications and Student Publications. The Unit Publications include brochures, bulletins, calendars, exhibition catalogs and student handbooks. Note that degree program requirements can be found in the Bulletin (Course Catalog) until 2001. Also note that the 1996 Bulletin covers the period from 1996 to 2001. After 2001, degree program requirements are contained within the Student Handbooks. Student Publications consist of catalogs and newsletters. Some publications (or their successors) may no longer be available in print but are available on the school s website.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. School of Art.; University of Michigan. School of Art and Design.; University of Michigan. College of Architecture and Design.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.
Genre Terms:
Brochures.; Bulletins.; Calendars.; Catalogs, College.; Exhibition catalogs.; Newsletters.; Student publications.
- Printed Material
  - Unit Publications
    - Annual Reports 1981-1984 (Box 1)
    - Brochures
      - Alumni Weekend, 1989 (Box 1)
      - Art and Architecture Building Site Plan, 1975 (Box 1)
      - Art and Design, 1967-1975 (Box 1)
      - Art Education, 1954 (Box 1)
      - Graduate Program Information, (Undated) (Box 1)
      - Miscellanea 1974-1992 (Box 1)
    - Bulletins (after 2001 see Student Handbooks)
      - College Catalogs
        - 1975-1977 (Box 1)
        - 1980-1981 (vol. 10, no. 6) (Box 1)
        - 1982-1984 (vol. 12, no. 2) (Box 1)
        - 1985-1987 (vol. 14, no. 4) (Box 1)
        - 1987-1992 (vol. 17, no. 3) (Box 1)
        - 1992-1994 (vol. 20, no. 13) (Box 1)
        - 1996-2001 (vol. 25, no. 16) (Box 1)
      - Bulletin Photographs 1989, undated (Box 1)
    - Calendars
      - This Month in the School of Art... 1989-2001 (Box 1)
    - Catalogs
      - Masters of Fine Art 2006-2007 (Box 1)
      - Undergraduate MFA Program 2006 (Box 1)
      - Zbigniew Libera Work 1984-2004 (Box 1)
    - Commencement Addresses 2003-2009 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Connections Program circa 2008 (Box 1)
    - Development Report 2001, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
    - Directories
      - Alumni 1990, 1995 (Box 1)
      - Faculty and Staff Directory 2001-2008 (Box 1)
    - Exhibition Catalogs
      - Alexander Corazzo/LeRoy Turner, American Abstraction-Creation: An Exhibition Organized by Gerome Kamrowski, 1976 (Box 1)
      - Alumni Art Annual, 1984, 2009 (Box 1)
      - A Circle of Life by Ruth Weisberg, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Faculty Art Exhibition
        - 1961-1965 (Box 1)
        - 1967 (Box 1)
        - 1975 (Box 1)
        - 1978 (Box 1)
      - Fiber, Metal and Clay: a Contemporary View, 1977 (Box 1)
      - Frontiers of Chaos, 1986 includes computer diskette (Box 1)
      - Fugitive Color, 1982 (Box 1)
      - Industrial Design Program, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
      - Invitational Exhibition: Sculpture Inside and Out, 1976 (Box 1)
      - "Margaret Watson Parker: A Collectors Legacy," 1982 (Box 1)
      - Photography: Faculty and Graduate Student Survey, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
      - Popular Art in America, 1953 (Box 1)
      - Senior Portfolio, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Profiles 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - Flyers and Postcards, various dates (Box 2)
    - Invitations, various dates (Box 2)
    - Manuals
      - By-Laws (Faculty) 1988-1990 (Box 2)
      - Untitled, (Undated) regarding use of computers in art (Box 2)
    - Newsletters
      - Alumni Newsletter, 1983-1988 (Box 2)
      - Alumni Report, 1975, 1977, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Emergence, 2005-ongoing (Box 2)
      - School of Art Alumni Report, 1975, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Stepping Out, 1974 (Box 2)
      - Visualize: the Newsletter of the School of Art
        - 1989-2000, 3 folders (Box 2)
        - Images circa 1994, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Reunion 50th 1958-2008 (Box 2)
    - Stamps (Penny W.) Lecture Series
      - 2001-2009 (Box 2)
    - Student Handbooks (includes Program Degree Requirements)
      - Freshman-Sophomore
        - 2004-2005 (Box 2)
      - Graduate Student
        - 2001-2007, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Graduate Handbook 2010-2011 (Box 2)
      - Handbook for New Students 1989-1991 (Box 2)
      - Undergraduate Student
        - 2000-2010 (Box 2)
    - Schedules, Summer Workshops 1994 (Box 2)
    - Senior Show, "Hello, My Name is," 2009 (Box 2)
    - Undergraduate Program, View books circa 2007 (Box 2)
  - Student Publications
    - Catalogs
      - Current Student Work, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Newsletters
      - Art Sense, 1992-1994, 3 folders (Box 2)
- School of Art & Design Archived Website
  The Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School of Art & Design. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website as of May 15, 2002, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
    (Original URL http://www.art-design.umich.edu/)
  - Website as of May 22, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived School of Art & Design home page 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the School of Art & Design 2010-[ongoing]